[upbeat jazzy music]
[欢快的爵士乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
♪ La-da-dee, la-da-da,
la-da-da ♪
♪ 拉-达-迪，拉-达-达，
啦啦啦啦♪
- [distant screaming]
- Uh-oh.
-[远处的尖叫声]
- 呃哦。
Incoming.
传入。
Ahh!
啊！
[groaning]
[呻吟]
[laughs]
[笑]
Plankton, you're a hot mess.
浮游生物，你真是一团糟。
Serves ya right
fer tryin' to steal me formular
为你服务吧
fer试图偷走我的公式
for the gazillionth time.
第无数次。
I'll have my revenge!
我一定会报仇的！
Mark my words!
记住我的话！
- [laughs]
- Aw, come on.
- [笑]
- 噢，来吧。
This isn't over!
这还没有结束！
[grunts]
- Oh, hard day at work?
[咕哝]
- 哦，工作辛苦了一天吗？
I know what you need.
我知道你需要什么。
Ahh!
啊！
[gasps]
[喘气]
[sighs]
[叹气]
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
Oh, Karen, I'm never gonna
get that Krabby Patty formula!
哦，凯伦，我永远不会
获取蟹黄派配方！
[sniffles, grunts]
[抽鼻子，咕哝]
Oops.
哎呀。
Mmm, not bad.
嗯，不错。
[laughter]
[笑声]
Enjoy your molten face peels!
享受你融化的脸部换肤吧！
Holy clambake!
神圣的蛤蜊！
Are Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy
是美人鱼男和藤壶男孩
about to become hero flambé
cooked by Man Ray
即将成为英雄flambé
由曼·雷烹饪
and his criminal posse
of E.V.I.L.?
和他的犯罪团伙
E.V.I.L.？
I hope so!
我希望如此！
I love it when the villains
gain the upper hand.
我喜欢当坏人的时候
占据上风。
[laughs]
[笑]
As our heroes face certain doom,
当我们的英雄面临某种厄运时，
the villains escape
坏人逃脱
to their secret
underground lair!
他们的秘密
地下巢穴！
[laughs]
[笑]
Of course!
当然！
All I need to do is
我需要做的就是
join the criminals
of E.V.I.L.!
加入犯罪分子的行列
邪恶之徒！
They'll help me defeat Krabs.
他们会帮助我打败蟹蟹。
Smart thinking.
聪明的思维。
You can go as "Towel Man."
你可以扮演“毛巾人”。
Don't be a wisenheimer.
不要成为一个明智的人。
I can't accessorize
this old rag.
我无法装饰
这块旧抹布。
I need a real costume.
我需要一套真正的服装。
♪ ♪
♪♪
Eh?
呃？
[buzzes]
[嗡嗡声]
Aw.
噢。
Ah!
啊!
[hisses]
[嘶嘶声]
[buzzes]
[嗡嗡声]
[growls]
[咆哮]
- [snarls]
- Ahh!
- [咆哮]
- 啊！
♪ ♪
♪♪
[laughs]
[笑]
[dings]
[叮当声]
[groans]
[呻吟]
Maybe a shorter cape.
也许是更短的斗篷。
♪ ♪
♪♪
This must be the entrance
to their secret lair.
这应该是入口
到他们的秘密巢穴。
A little dumpster dive,
and I'm in.
一个小小的垃圾箱潜水，
我进来了。
[groans]
[呻吟]
Ah.
啊。
[straining]
[紧张]
[groans]
Where's the door?
[呻吟]
门在哪里？
Ooh?
哦？
♪ ♪
♪♪
Wrong dumpster.
错误的垃圾箱。
[sighs]
Of course.
[叹气]
当然。
♪ ♪
♪♪
Hello?
[laughs]
你好？
[笑]
I'm here
to join the forces of E.V.I.L.!
我在这里
加入 E.V.I.L. 的势力！
♪ ♪
♪♪
- Dude.
- Huh, wha...
- 伙计。
- 呃，什么...
Sign in and wait your turn.
登录并等待轮到您。
Red leather, yellow leather.
红色皮革，黄色皮革。
Get out of the car, fellas!
下车吧，伙计们！
Take all your money
and put it in the bag!
拿走你所有的钱
并把它放进包里！
No, Mr. Bob.
不，鲍勃先生。
I expect you to fry.
[cackles]
我期待着你去炒。
[咯咯笑]
- When the full moon rises...
- I am the Strangler!
- 当满月升起时...
- 我是绞杀者！
- [vocalizing]
- [clears throat]
- [发声]
- [清喉咙]
I'm the Strangler.
- [growling]
我是绞杀者。
- [咆哮]
- What is this yellow thing?
- [babbling]
- 这个黄色的东西是什么？
- [胡言乱语]
Some kind of mold?
某种模具？
To be or... line!
成为或...线！
[growls, grunts]
Ha.
[咆哮，咕哝]
哈。
[roars]
[怒吼]
We've got quite an impressive
rogues gallery up there, eh?
我们有一个令人印象深刻的
那里有盗贼画廊，嗯？
Thank you for taking time out
of your scandalous schedules
感谢您抽出时间
你可耻的日程安排
to try out for E.V.I.L.
尝试 E.V.I.L.
As you all know,
众所周知，
we can only pick one new villain
我们只能选择一个新的反派
to join Team E.V.I.L.,
加入E.V.I.L.团队，
so let the judging begin!
那么让评判开始吧！
♪ ♪
♪♪
Eeny, meeny, miney... [grunts]
哎尼，米尼，我的……[咕哝]
Nosferatu!
诺斯费拉图！
[hissing]
[嘶嘶声]
No way, Man Ray!
不可能，曼·雷！
I was first!
我是第一个！
First to go bye-bye.
[cackles]
首先要告别。
[咯咯笑]
Huh?
[screams]
啊？
[尖叫声]
[all gasp]
- Be gone!
[全都喘气]
- 走开！
[blows]
[打击]
Nosferatu, proceed.
诺斯费拉图，继续。
[eerie music]
[怪异音乐]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[dramatic piano music]
[戏剧性的钢琴音乐]
♪ ♪
Mime?
哑剧？
Mime is his evil power?
哑剧是他的邪恶力量吗？
Ahh!
啊！
Robot Mantis!
机器人螳螂！
[mumbles]
[咕哝]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
[babbling]
[胡说]
[somber cello music]
[忧郁的大提琴音乐]
[babbling]
[胡说]
[country violin music]
[乡村小提琴音乐]
[babbling]
[胡说]
[mellow banjo music]
[柔和的班卓琴音乐]
[babbling]
[胡说]
[upbeat kazoo music]
[欢快的卡祖笛音乐]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
Ta-da!
哒哒！
How dare you!
你怎么敢！
We just had that piano tuned!
我们刚刚调好钢琴！
Ahh!
啊！
Eeny, meeny, miney... [grunts]
哎尼，米尼，我的……[咕哝]
Sheldon J. Plankton?
谢尔顿·J·浮游生物？
[dramatic kazoo music]
[戏剧性的卡祖笛音乐]
Thanks, ma'am, but, uh,
music won't be necessary.
谢谢，女士，但是，呃，
音乐将不再是必需的。
[grunts]
- Right.
[咕哝]
- 对。
So what's your supervillain
power, little guy?
那么你的超级恶棍是什么
力量，小家伙？
Well, I'd venture to say
好吧，我斗胆说
it would be my massive,
evil intellect.
这将是我的巨大，
邪恶的智力。
Impressive.
感人的。
So where do you see yourself
in the next five years?
那么你在哪里看到自己
未来五年？
Well, once I finally have
the secret formula...
好吧，一旦我终于拥有了
秘密公式...
[crowd screaming]
[人群尖叫]
The post-apocalyptic
global empire
后世界末日
全球帝国
of destruction
that results will be mine,
破坏的
结果将是我的，
and I'll be sitting pretty
on a pile of your bones!
我会坐得很漂亮
在你的一堆骨头上！
[cackles]
[咯咯笑]
That sounds pretty villainous.
这听起来很邪恶。
Okay, you'll move on
to the test phase.
好的，你会继续前进
到测试阶段。
But first, you'll need
a proper supervillain name.
但首先，你需要
一个合适的超级恶棍的名字。
How about "Mr. Green Bean"?
《绿豆先生》怎么样？
Ooh,
the "Itsy Bitsy Green Guy."
哦，
“Itsy Bitsy Green Guy”。
No, too long.
[bell dings]
不，太长了。
[铃声]
How about "Captain Pipsqueak"?
《皮普船长》怎么样？
- Yeah!
- I love it!
- 是的！
- 我喜欢它！
[laughter]
- That settles it.
[笑声]
=> - 这就解决了。
Captain Pipsqueak!
皮普斯奎克船长！
all: Captain Pipsqueak!
全体：皮普斯奎克船长！
We can tweak that later, right?
我们可以稍后调整，对吗？
[screams]
[尖叫声]
Okay, team, let's test
Captain Pipsqueak's villainy
好的，团队，让我们测试一下
皮普斯奎克船长的恶行
in the real world.
在现实世界中。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
Your first test is
to get us lunch:
你的第一个测试是
为我们准备午餐：
a 25-pound bucket
from Weenie Hut Jr.
25磅重的水桶
来自 小威尼小屋
[cackles]
- With Evil sauce.
[咯咯笑]
- 配上邪恶的酱汁。
Extra Evil sauce.
[laughs]
额外的邪恶酱。
[笑]
Odd caper, but no problemo.
奇怪的举动，但没问题。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[bell dinging]
[铃声]
I need a 25-pound
Weenie bucket, please,
我需要一个25磅的
维尼桶，拜托，
and make it snappy!
并让它变得敏捷！
Oh, and extra Evil sauce.
哦，还有额外的邪恶酱。
Hey, I know that order.
嘿，我知道这个顺序。
You're one
of those E.V.I.L. guys.
你是一个
那些 E.V.I.L.伙计们。
You're all banned!
你们都被禁止了！
Just give me my order,
只要给我我的订单，
or you'll know the meaning
of fear!
不然你就会知道其中的意义
恐惧！
[whistles]
Security!
[口哨声]
安全！
We got a small problem here.
我们这里遇到了一个小问题。
[light music]
[轻音乐]
Oh?
哦？
Ahh!
[grunting]
啊！
[咕噜声]
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
[all grumbling]
- So boring.
[大家都在抱怨]
- 太无聊了。
Short legs.
We should've known better.
腿短。
我们应该更清楚。
I'm starving here!
我这里快饿死了！
What are the chances
he gets our food?
有什么机会
他得到我们的食物吗？
Slim to none, I'm guessing.
我猜，瘦到没有。
Hello?
你好？
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Could somebody help me
with this?
有人可以帮助我吗
与这个？
[all munching]
[全都在咀嚼]
Oh, and extra Evil sauce.
哦，还有额外的邪恶酱。
- Wicked.
- Awesome.
- 邪恶的。
- 惊人的。
A Weenie toast
to Captain Pipsqueak.
维尼吐司
皮普斯奎克船长。
all: Pip pip hooray!
全体： 皮皮皮万岁！
[groaning]
[呻吟]
Okay, Cap,
好吧，卡普，
take this bag of snail droppings
拿走这袋蜗牛粪便
and leave it
on that doorstep over there.
并留下它
就在那边的门口。
It's the house of the Foot.
这是脚的房子。
He's a superhero do-gooder
who deserves our worst.
他是一位超级英雄、行善者
谁该承受我们最坏的惩罚。
Go!
去！
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
[laughter]
[笑声]
Yes.
[cackles]
是的。
[咯咯笑]
I added a little
我加了一点
of my own special Chum Mix
to the bag.
我自己的特殊密友混合
到袋子里。
Captain Pipsqueak,
welcome to E.V.I.L.,
皮普斯奎克船长，
欢迎来到 E.V.I.L.，
which stands for...
它代表...
"Every Villain Is Lemons."
“每个恶棍都是柠檬。”
- Yeah!
- Whoo!
- 是的！
- 呼！
So Captain Pipsqueak,
what's next?
所以皮普斯奎克船长，
接下来会发生什么？
[cackles]
[咯咯笑]
Follow me to world domination!
跟随我，称霸世界！
[cackles]
[咯咯笑]
♪ ♪
♪♪
- Huh?
- [laughs]
- 啊？
- [笑]
[gasps]
Mr. Krabs!
[喘气]
蟹老板！
- What now, boy?
- [groans]
- 现在怎么办，孩子？
- [呻吟]
Shiver me's lumbers!
颤抖我的木头！
[upbeat jazzy music]
[欢快的爵士乐]
[cackling]
[咯咯笑]
Yah!
[laughs]
啊！
[笑]
[cackling]
[咯咯笑]
Heh, heh.
呵呵。
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
[customers gasping]
[顾客喘气]
[laughs]
[笑]
You might as well give us
the secret formula now, Krabs.
你不妨给我们
现在秘密配方，蟹蟹。
I'm the new mastermind
of E.V.I.L.
我是新的主谋
E.V.I.L. 的
[laughs]
[笑]
What, you nerds going
to a comic convention?
什么，你们这些书呆子要去
参加漫画大会？
Ooh, that is a nice costume, Plankton.
哦，这服装真不错，痞游生物。
[laughs]
[笑]
The name is Captain Pipsqueak
to you.
我的名字是皮普斯奎克船长
给你。
Get 'em!
- [laughs]
抓住他们！
- [笑]
- Whoa, whoa!
- [gasps]
- 哇，哇！
- [喘气]
[muffled]
- Dirty Bubble?
[低声]
- 肮脏的泡泡？
But I just did my laundry.
但我刚刚洗完衣服。
Thieves!
小偷！
Keep yer filthy, rotten mitts
保留你肮脏、腐烂的手套
offa me formular.
奥法我公式。
[laughs]
[笑]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[laughs]
Yes.
[笑]
是的。
Yes!
是的！
[cackles]
[咯咯笑]
Huh?
啊？
This isn't the formula
for world domination.
这不是公式
为了统治世界。
It's a recipe for a sandwich!
这是三明治的食谱！
How does that work?
这是如何运作的？
Uh, well, with that,
I can put this guy...
呃，好吧，有了这个，
我可以把这个人...
- [growls]
- Outta business.
- [咆哮]
- 没生意了。
Mmm, why would we
ever wanna do that?
嗯，我们为什么要
有想过这样做吗？
These Krabby Patties
taste great!
这些蟹肉饼
味道好极了！
Yeah, mmm.
是的，嗯。
- [spits]
- Mmm.
- [吐口水]
- 嗯。
[chewing]
[咀嚼]
- Mmm.
- 嗯。
Here you go, boss.
Sorry about that.
给你，老板。
对此感到抱歉。
Keep up the good work.
继续做好工作。
I can't believe
this lousy pipsqueak...
我不敢相信
这个可恶的小吱吱……
- Huh?
- Wasted our time!
- 啊？
- 浪费了我们的时间！
- Some criminal genius he is.
- Right?
- 他是个犯罪天才。
- 正确的？
"Massive evil intellect,"
my eye.
“巨大的邪恶智力，”
我的眼睛。
- Nyah!
- Holy habanero!
- 呀！
- 神圣的哈瓦那！
Is Plankton forever doomed
浮游生物是否永远注定要灭亡
to be bound by a bottle?
被瓶子束缚？
- Ahh!
- Grounded in glass?
- 啊！
- 接地玻璃？
No!
- Ahh, ahh!
不！
- 啊啊啊！
Enveloped by extra Evil sauce!
被额外的邪恶酱汁包围！
[laughter]
[笑声]
No outside condiments!
没有外面的调味品！
[groans]
[呻吟]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
Well, this stinks.
嗯，这很臭。
♪ ♪
♪♪